Forty-seven!
And 50!
Out of 50 chops, I only
heard three good ones there.
So far, that brings your total to 41.
Sorry, Yu-Gi-Oh.
Looks like the cereal water's
on you. Again. Oh, whatever.
You got, what, 43 good chops so far?
I'll catch up soon. Go on.
It's your turn at the axe, Kirito.
Yeah, in a sec.
Every day for the past
year and three months,
we've been hacking away at this darn tree.
I can't take it anymore.
There's no use complaining about it.
Our calling's to cut the giga-cedar
down, so there's no getting out of it.
Yeah, I know you're right, but still.
It doesn't feel like
we're getting anywhere.
That's its life now.
What was it two months ago?
I think it was at 235,590?
I'm gonna be sick.
After two months of chopping at it,
we only got its life down a lousy 50!
It's gonna take us forever to cut it down!
What do you expect?
This tree's as strong as steel.
Six generations of carvers worked
on it for 300 years to get this far.
It'll get cut down.
In 900 years or so.
Oh, is that all?
Well...
What are you doing?
You think you're such a smarty-pants.
Why don't you use that big brain of yours
to figure out how to
get us out of this job?
Would you...
Stop it!
Get off!
Now it's my turn!
How'd you like that?
Want more or do you give up?
Not even!
Hit payback time!
No surrender!
No, stop it! Nope.
I knew I'd find you boys goofing off.
Tonkii it.
Oh, hi, Alice.
Did your sacred arts
class let out early today?
Cause, like, you're early.
I'm not early at all.
I'm right on time.
Since you have the energy to wrestle,
maybe I should tell old man Kirito to
add some more swings to your daily quota.
No, not that.
Anything but that.
I'm just kidding.
Here.
It's time you had some lunch.
It's so hot today.
You better eat it fast before it spoils.
Okay.
The pie sure tastes good today.
Alice, your cooking keeps
getting better. For real.
Oh, I don't know.
It turned out okay, I guess,
but it could have been better.
You know what?
If anything, I wish we could take our
time eating this instead of rushing.
Why does food have to spoil
so fast when it's hot?
Because it's hot.
I know that.
But in winter, we leave raw meat out and
it keeps for days as long as it's salted.
Well, yeah.
That's because it's cold in winter.
That's right.
And if we could keep food cold in
summer, too, it would last way longer.
But to make it snow, you'd have to use
the forbidden weather-altering arts, too.
Then an Integrity Knight from the Axiom
Church would come and take you away.
Ice. That's it.
Huh? Don't you see?
If we had lots of ice, we
could keep the food cold.
Then we could take our time
and enjoy Alice's lunches.
I say we go have ourselves a quest.
A quest for ice.
Honestly, it's summer now.
Where would you find
ice this time of year?
Even the market at Senator is out.
Wait, remember that story about one
of the village founders, Bercoli?
Which story?
You know, Bercoli and the
Northern White Dragon.
He followed the Rural River
all the way to its source,
the cave at the foot of the End Mountains.
He went in and found a pile of treasure
with a big white dragon sleeping on top.
Then, he grabbed a sword sticking out
of the treasure, and the dragon woke up.
The story also says he saw giant icicles
a little ways past the mouth of the cave.
I say we go and get them.
That's crazy.
That's not a bad idea.
Wait, you too?
Come on, you know the law of the village.
It says we can't...
Yes, I know it.
It says kids aren't allowed
to play anywhere near the
End Mountains unless they
have a grown-up with them.
But if we're there looking
for ice, that's not playing.
If our village had ice,
all the food would last longer
and that would benefit everyone.
So if we went to get some, it'd
be considered work, not play.
She's right.
It'd totally be work.
Maybe but we wouldn't just be breaking
the village's law by going up there.
We'd be breaking the other one too.
What?
Don't play dumb.
The taboo index.
No one's allowed to.
You're right, but here's what
it says about the End Mountains.
In book 1, chapter 3, verse 11,
the index says none shall
cross the end mountains?
that surround the human empire.
By cross,
it means entering the dark territory
on the other side of the End Mountains.
It doesn't say anything
about going in the cave.
Yeah, but...
Ow!
That settles it.
This will be the end of the cave.
weekend we'll find that dra
- I mean, find that ice cave.
Okay, let's meet in
the morning at seven by
the north gate.
You got it, and don't
oversleep. Oh, please.
Making us carry everything.
Who does she think we are, her servants?
Stop complaining.
Be happy we can still go
and do stuff with her.
That'll end soon
Why?
She's the village elder's
daughter, that's why.
She has to learn all that stuff
a lady's supposed to know.
Like manners and etiquette.
Yeah,
and since she wasn't
given a calling like we
were She has to study all
those sacred art skills,
too.
She's going to be a role
model for the villagers.
That means no more playing
with us boys anymore.
All right.
What are the two of you
whispering about back there?
Nothing Right? Right Right.
We were just saying how
we'd get in trouble if
we don't make it back
before the evening bell.
Oh, good point.
Then keep an eye on Solus, and when it's
in the middle of the sky, we'll head back.
Come on, guys.
Back to our quest!
We're pretty far from the village now.
Did you know back in the olden days,
back when Rulid was first founded?
goblins and orcs came down
from the Dark Territory,
raided the village and stole
a bunch of sheep and kids.
Listen, if you're trying
to scare me, stop it.
I know the story.
An Integrity Knight came from Senator
and chased them all away in the end.
That's right.
And ever since,
on clear days you'll see a Silver Dragon
Knight soaring above the End Mountains,
ever vigilant.
We all saw that, right?
It's the cave!
We reached the Yen Mountains.
Let's go in.
It's why we came here after all.
System Call.
Generate Luminous Elements. Adhere!
Well, I don't see any icicles yet.
Didn't you say they were
supposed to be a little ways in?
I don't know, did I? You did!
Yu-Gi-Oh?
Yeah?
Could you please bring
that light over here?
Whoa!
See that?
It's colder now.
You're right, it totally is.
For a second there, I thought I
was coming down with something.
It's kind of neat how it's winter
in here, but summer outside.
I bet we'll find some ice further in.
Yeah, hopefully not too much further in.
What are we going to do if we happen
to come across a white dragon?
We'll run away as fast as we can.
Quit worrying.
I seriously doubt it's going to
mind if we take a couple icicles.
Hmm, it'd be neat if we could
grab one of its scales though?
No, we are not doing that!
Why not?
How else are we going to prove
we saw a real live dragon?
Look, it's ice.
It's true, there's ice in here.
And I bet you guys there's
even more up ahead!
Do you see that?
With this much ice, we can keep
all the food in the village cold.
Heck, with this much ice, you can keep
the whole Tonkii village cold forever.
Jeez, would you watch where you're going?
Huchio, look.
There it is.
Whoa.
The dragon?
No way.
How did it die?
Look.
Its claws all covered in gouges.
And then it was chopped clean off.
Then it must have fought with something.
But I don't know of anything
that could kill a dragon.
A sword made these marks.
It's obvious what killed it. A human.
But who?
If a sword master like
Bercouli couldn't fight it,
who'd be strong enough to kill it?
An Integrity Knight?
But why?
The White Dragons protect our realm.
Why would an Integrity Knight
from the Axiom Church kill one?
Wait a second.
Maybe the Dark Territory has strong
knights too, and one of them killed it.
If that's true,
then the Armies of Darkness could easily
cross the End Mountains and attack us.
Wait! What are you doing?
This is heavier than it looks!
Is that the sword? Yeah.
The same one Bercouli tried to steal.
The Blue Rose Sword.
It's too heavy.
I can't lift it.
Even with Eugeo's help, we'd
never carry this back to town.
There's a bunch of other
treasure we could take, though.
Mm-hmm.
But something about
that doesn't feel right.
It would be like grave robbing.
Yeah, I guess you're right.
We'll just take ice.
The dragon won't mind that.
How pretty.
It's a shame it's just
going to end up melting.
I couldn't care less as long as
it makes our meals last longer.
Not just our meals, everyone's.
We should start heading back now, or else
we won't make it to town before dark.
You're right.
Wait, do you remember which
tunnel we came in from?
We've been walking a long time.
Is this the right tunnel,
or was it the other?
Seriously?
We picked this one because
you said we should.
What?
I didn't hear you.
Uh, never mind.
Shh.
Is that the wind?
You picked the right path.
We're almost to the entrance.
Wait!
Be careful or you'll
trip and hurt yourself!
There it is!
Where are we?
The dark territory.
Oh, no.
We better turn around.
Dragon Knights!
That white one.
That's a real-life
Integrity Knight, isn't it?
And the others from the Dark Territory.
Oh, my God.
No, wait!
Alice!
In Book 1, Chapter 3, Verse 11,
the index says, None shall cross the End
Mountains that surround the human empire.
Alice!
What have I done?
Don't worry, Alice. It's okay.
I mean, it's not like you left the cave.
You didn't.
She didn't, did she?
Kirito?
What's that?
A singular unit has been detected.
Tracing its ID.
Coordinates fixed.
Report complete.
What was that thing?
I don't know.
Let's get out of here.
So, guys, where are we going to put this?
I'll put the ice in my basement
where it's nice and cool.
Okay, see ya.
I think tomorrow's lunch will
be the best one yet. Can't wait.
Me neither.
Alice...
Don't go!
Alice!
I don't know.
An Integrity Knight!
Yeah, he's the same one from yesterday.
Oh no, Alice.
He's come for her.
But he can't take her away for that!
Come on!
Wait!
Alice!
Kirito! Yu-Gi-Oh! Keep it down.
Better get out of here before he sees you.
It's my father.
I am Gosfut Zuburg, the
elder of this village.
I am Deo Selbert Synthesis 7,
the Axiom Integrity Knight who oversees
the northern Norlingarth territory.
Your daughter, Alice Zuburg,
has disobeyed the taboo index.
I shall take her with me to answer
for her crimes and be executed.
Taboo Index,
Book 1, Chapter 3, Verse 11 states, None
shall cross into the dark territory.
Sir Knight!
Alice never set foot
in the Dark Territory.
It was an accident.
All she did was touch the ground.
It was only for a second.
That is enough to charge
her with the crime.
Then we're just as guilty as she is.
We were right there with her.
If you take her, then take us too.
Yu-Gi-Oh, listen, I'm gonna
charge him with the axe.
Grab Alice and run.
Hold on, I don't, we can't.
I don't care what happens.
Her life's more important
than some stupid old rules.
Kirito!
Escort those two children from the square.
Let her go!
Don't just stand there! Go help her!
U-U-Gio, get these guys off me!
Come on, hurry!
U-U-Gio!
Oh, my God.
Let's go.
This turning costume is full auto!
What's up, you PK jerks?
Let's see how fast you run!
Cowards!
You're up! I'll cover!
Are those Photon Swords?
Team A needs backup.
B and C, head to Grid 4-6.
You have permission to
use grenades. Hey, boss.
Let me in on this.
No, this op's about to wind down.
Just sit back and watch.
I got this!
Damn it.
Well, that's the end of that.
All teams retreat.
Grid 1-9's too hot.
We could have killed them
all if we stuck with it.
You sure you want to end
the day like this, boss?
That team's all over the place.
Fighting them won't
help with our training.
We have the big mission coming
up and we need to stay sharp.
Let's go.
Till next time, kid.
Oh, man, I heard GGO was going to
be hardcore, but that was insane.
I never played a game where it's
cool just to run around and kill.
Actually, there's a method
to the madness of PKing here.
You go after other players
for their cashier items.
But the team we just fought
didn't care about that stuff.
Yeah, the only thing those guys
wanted was to straight up kill us.
And did you see all the grenades
and smoke bombs they used?
Isn't that stuff expensive?
You know it.
And that's how they fight
every single time they show up.
They go after teams that are out in the
middle of nowhere, massacre everyone,
then disappear without looting anyone.
I saw their stats.
Is it true they've never lost a battle?
Yeah, it's true they haven't.
Still, I thought if anyone
could beat them, we could.
Because as a team, we're not like
anyone they've come up against yet.
Oh well, I guess it just
wasn't in the cards.
I didn't expect they'd
retreat, that's for sure.
Hey, no biggie.
It's not like we lost.
Besides, they ran, so
that's a win in my book.
The point was to find out who they were
and what they were up to, tough guy.
Yeah, well, a win's a win.
That said, it would have been nice
to find out the leader's name.
Yeah, but with the way they fought, it
wasn't even clear who the leader was.
Hey, don't flap on me.
Oh, I look like a pillow.
But he said he's been taking time off from
school since Thursday
and touring companies.
Knowing him, he's probably mixed
up in something sinister again.
Thanks again for helping me
out, guys. You're the best.
No problems. Anytime. Later.
Today was fun. See ya.
Well, bye. No, wait. One sec. What's up?
I was hoping you guys could
help me with something.
That squad of PKers?
No, it's something else, actually.
If you and Kirito have time,
could we meet IRL tomorrow?
I think so.
Yeah, I'm free in the evening.
Do you want to meet at Aikyo's?
Sure.
Oh, I'll also email you the plan so
you can think about it, if that's okay.
Sounds good.
You're so thin.
Are you eating?
What are you, my mom?
Anyway, what is it you wanted to ask me?
Is it about B .O .B.? Mm-hmm.
There's a player calling himself
Sutilizer who won B .O .B.
4.
He's the same guy who
won the first B .O .B.
Huh.
When we found out he was in 4,
everyone got excited because
he's like a legend, you know?
Yeah, we all watched the live feed.
Can't believe he started
with just his bare hands.
He fought with a confident, stealthy
style, like that team from the other day.
They did have the same vibe, didn't they?
Well, except subtilizers on a
whole other level than them.
He killed me so fast.
I didn't even have time to aim.
That's how it was for
everyone in the tourney.
It's like he knew our moves before we did.
No way, really?
Really?
But you're all vets at B .O .B.
How could he anticipate
everyone's moves like that?
I suppose as vets there's a
predictability to how we play.
We tend to use the same
moves because they work.
Which brings me to why you're here.
I was thinking that a player
with a more chaotic fighting
style might have a better chance
at outmaneuvering Settilizer.
Anyway, the point is, the next B .O .B.
is going to be happening at the end of the
year, and I'd like you to sign up for it.
Huh? Uh...
There's no way I'm gonna let
myself lose to the same guy again.
He's going down.
Looks like you made some progress.
Oh, yeah.
I still get the shakes every now
and then, but I'm getting better.
And your friend.
Is he doing any better?
You mean Shinkawa.
Yeah, he's making progress.
I'll probably go visit him
again in a couple days.
That's good.
Well, look on the bright side.
He's finally getting the help he needs.
Death Gun's over.
No, it isn't.
His partner's still out there, remember?
Yeah, but Kikuoka said they'll
catch up with him soon enough.
Yeah, I hope so.
Sorry I'm late.
Hey there, Shinanon.
What'd you just call her?
Hey, Asuna. Right on time.
I read your email about
B .O .B. 5. I'm in.
Wait, you asked her to help, too? Yep.
I figured if it were just you,
there's a chance you'd get to aggro.
Even good dogs need a
leash, right? Tonkii.
Hey, Kirito?
You're so thin.
Are you eating?
Yeah, I am.
Ha! See?
She can even tell something's up.
It's that part-time job, isn't it?
Honestly.
Physically, you're fine, so far.
Wait, you can tell?
What's that?
It's exactly what it looks like.
Huh?
You mean she can track your vitals?
Neat, huh?
Yeah, I guess.
But, like, how's it work?
A little while ago, I had this
miniature sensor implanted in my chest.
It sends my heart rate,
body temperature, and other stuff
over the net to us in a smartphone.
What?
Why would you want to do...
Oh, I get it.
It's an anti-cheating system.
No, not even.
When I started this part-time job,
they thought it'd be good to get it.
I have to wear electrodes
and sticking them
on and pulling them off
is kind of a hassle.
Using it like this was her idea,
so I made a little app for it.
Yeah, something about looking
at it's kind of soothing.
Knowing that's Kirito's heart beating.
I get all woozy and my
head starts to spin.
That's both cute and kind of creepy.
Anyway, with you on my side, I'll
have a machine gun in my pillbox.
You're exactly the edge I need.
I'm happy to help any way I can.
Now then. What?
I want to hear some more about
this sketchy new job of yours.
Let me guess, you're alpha
testing a new VR MMO game, right?
Actually, it's not a game.
It's a brain-machine interface designed
for this brand new full dive system.
Rath developed it. They're new.
What the heck kind of a name is Rath?
It's the name of an imaginary creature.
I remember it from the book
Through the Looking Glass.
Some characters said it was
a pig and others a turtle.
So, are they releasing some
next-gen full-dive rig for gaming?
I don't know. Maybe.
This thing's totally different compared
to the full-dive tech that's out now.
Oh.
So, what's the in-game world like?
I have no idea.
Huh?
It's how they keep things confidential.
The memories I make using
their rig in the VR world,
they don't stick with
me in the real world.
Whatever I saw during the
tests, whatever I did,
I'd forget all of it after I log out.
Huh?
You can't remember anything at all?
Oh my god, is it another Ogma?
No, it's not like that.
This rig doesn't put stress on
your brain like the Ogma did.
I didn't lose my memories or anything, I
just can't access them from my Fluct light.
A Fluct what?
This is going to take
some time to explain.
First off, the rig I'm testing
is called the Soul Translator.
Where in your body do
you think your soul is?
Seriously?
I don't know.
In the brain?
If you zoom into the brain,
you'll see it's made up of cells.
So, where in all those cells
do you think the soul is?
I don't know.
Zoom into a brain cell
and you'll see that it has
things in it that support
the cell's structure.
They're called microtubules.
Okay.
Like the name implies,
they're like hollow pipes.
But they're not empty.
They got something sealed inside.
So, what do they have inside?
Light.
That's it.
Fluctuating light.
It's the building block of the
human soul, according to Rath.
So let me see if I understand this.
They're saying this light in brain cells.
That's the soul? Yeah.
They don't call it a
soul at Wrath, though.
They decided to go with a combination
of the words fluctuating and light.
Fluctlight for short.
And the Soul Translator doesn't
just read a person's brain,
it reads their Fluctlight.
Which means it can also
imprint on them. Imprint?
Like the atmosphere.
That rig lets you experience
VR by sending images,
sounds, and other sensory
information to your brain.
With this rig,
since it's next-gen and all, it would
work the same way but on your soul, right?
Yeah, that's right.
The name pretty much says it all.
The Soul Translator, or STL,
writes short-term memories
onto your Fluctlight
of the sights and sounds
it wants you to experience.
Mnemonic visual data is what it's called.
I remember the test dives I took
at the beginning of the job.
Those dives were different.
I was blown away.
It's nothing like what
the Amusphere creates.
Everything was so real, I couldn't
tell it was a virtual world at first.
I don't know.
This scares me.
I mean, is it safe?
Mr.
Kikuoka offered you the job, and that's
great, but who knows what his motives are.
Yeah, you're right, but I don't
let my guard down around him ever.
The thing is, I want to know.
I have to do this to see
where full dive's heading.
I know it's risky, but the STL's special.
Sure, terms like mnemonic and flukplight
sound creepy, but I connect with it.
Way more than the atmosphere.
It's like a waking dream
when I'm in it. How so?
You know how you sometimes
have dreams that seem long?
The kind where you wake up and you'd
swear that dream went on for hours,
especially if it was a nightmare?
The truth is, that dream probably
only lasted a few minutes.
You get that same phenomena if
you dive with the STL. Seriously?
It's just like a dream that felt like
hours but was only a few minutes.
Your time diving with the STL
is way longer than your dive.
That's the main feature of the STL.
Wrath calls it Fluctlight
Acceleration, or FLA for short.
Whoa.
I'm so confused.
My head's spinning.
You were diving for three whole days,
so how much time was that in VR?
I'm not sure.
It could have been ten days or a month.
I don't remember how long.
When I asked how long,
they wouldn't tell me.
But they did tell me the
codename of the test world.
Really?
What is it?
The Underworld.
So it's like an underground
world? It's a reference.
It has to do with Alice, same as Raph.
Alice in Wonderland was the title
the book was published under,
but it had a different title
when it was being written.
Originally, it was called
Alice's Adventures Underground.
You okay?
When I heard the name Alice, it felt
like I was about to remember something.
Something about the test?
I'm not sure.
It feels like there's
something I need to do.
I just can't remember what.
Thanks, Egil. See you later.
Bye, guys.
I'll keep you guys up
to date about B .O .B.
Thanks again for meeting up with me today.
Sure.
See you later, Sheenanone.
See ya.
That was fun.
What's wrong? Say what?
Oh, nothing.
Talk to me.
Asuna.
I think I'm gonna go.
To America? Yeah.
The research is way more advanced there.
It's all next-gen stuff.
They're creating a new world, and
I want to be there when it's born.
We were happy in Aincrad, but there
was so much pain and sadness, too.
You want to find out why that
castle still haunts your thoughts,
and where that experience is taking you.
Even if I lived a couple hundred
years, I doubt I'd ever find that out.
Anyway, I want...
I want you with me, Asuna. Always.
I want you to come with me, and I...
I know that's asking a
lot, but the truth is...
I can't do this without you!
Of course, I'll go anywhere with you.
It doesn't matter where.
I'll go.
Asuna.
So does this mean the Soul
Translator isn't the next step in VR?
Hearing you talk about
it, I thought it was.
I don't know.
For some reason, I get the feeling its
purpose isn't just a full dive in VR worlds.
Then what's it for?
A tool for learning about
Fluctlights and human consciousness.
It's like,
whatever I know about
the STL makes me think
it might be an extension
of Kayaba's ideas.
He's behind it?
I don't know why he made the NerveGear and
SAO to trap everyone
and make us all suffer.
Or why he'd fry his own brain.
And the seed.
He didn't make it just
to keep Fairy alive.
I want to know what his endgame was.
But I don't want it to be mine.
I'm not his puppet.
And if I go down that road, I would be.
You said you talked to him.
Or the part of him he left behind. Yeah.
I think I know why he left
a copy of himself out there.
And it might have something to do
with what Wrath's up to with the STL.
Hey, sorry to bother you.
I'm sort of lost.
Where's the station?
Oh, just down there.
Kirito?
You followed us from Dicey's cafe.
There goes my plan to ambush y 'all.
Who are you?
Oh, come on, Kirito.
Don't you recognize me?
Oh, that's right.
I always wore a mask back there.
Yeah, now that Zaza's been caught, there's
no one left to finish things but me.
The last survivor of Laughing Coffin.
Johnny Black.
You ass!
You got no sword here!
So, you're still on the run?
Of course!
Damn, Kirito.
I can't believe you're the same
dude that beat the hell out of us!
But you're just a punk-ass kid, ain't ya?
Take away your swords, and you're nothing.
What about you?
You don't have your poison dagger.
I don't.
You sure about that, Kirito?
Death gun!
Run! Get out of here!
Kirito!
Kirito
beginning
SHINING SOMER DIAMOND
Next time, the Demon Tree.